I consider Adam my brother.
He is so hostile towards you.
Adam is hostile
toward everyone.
Don't you even
want to see her try?
I've seen enough
people quit in my lifetime
without witnessing
the same thing again.
I think she'll surprise you.
I am attempting
to find my place here
and claim a degree of
equanimity with my new husband.
I am for Hawick
in the morning.
Is something the
matter with Harry?
He's taken exceedingly ill
at an inn between
here and Hawick.
What are you intending to do?
Go retrieve him. of course.
Why did you not allow a
physician to be summoned?
This gentleman is clearly ill.
I ain't running
a charity. guv.
Here's hoping we can do
business again in the future.
We will.
He is so confusing.
All part of his
charm. Persephone.
What in the blazes
is wrong with me?
This has arrived
for you as well.
Persephone?
Evander is dead.
Harry was as
impertinent as ever
when I saw him
an hour or so ago.
Take that as an indication
that he is recovering.
I received a letter
from my sister today.
Which one?
Artemis.
The youngest?
Yes.
She dislikes her governess.
but not for any
legitimate reason.
She feels weighed down
by the continued state of
mourning around the house.
And she has asked. again. to
be able to come here to visit.
I suggested spring or summer.
Of course. nothing has
actually been planned.
We'll have to go to
London in the spring.
After enduring Society
and the Season.
it will be good to return
here where it's quiet.
Yes.
It is decidedly quiet.
How are you feeling?
Mm. much improved.
Being away from
the Boar and Dagger
has contributed
greatly to my welfare.
Then you'll be pleased to know
it will not be a source
of misery any longer.
It is to be shuttered
immediately.
- Shuttered?
- Mm.
A closer look at Smith's
history and practices
made closing the place
absolutely necessary.
Any man who would withhold
food. warmth. medical aid.
even the ability
to send for help
when a person is in distress.
and has done so time and again.
ought not be running an inn.
Mm.
First you rush to the rescue.
then you vanquish the
villain who tortured me.
Watch yourself. Adam.
People will begin
to think you care.
Shut up. Harry.
Barton!
What is that infernal noise?
I believe that
would be described
as lively conversation.
Your Grace.
And who is responsible for
such lively conversation?
Mrs. Pointer.
No doubt the
vicar is here as well.
No doubt.
Are you feeling quite
yourself today. Barton?
I assure you
I-I feel better than I
have in years. Your Grace.
It sounds as though Falstone
is infested with birds.
A full tea?
I believe cook was
exceptionally excited
at the prospect of preparing
a tea tray once more.
It's been a while. Your Grace.
How is it. Barton. that
the vicar and his wife
came to be in my drawing room?
I do not recall altering
the requirement
that all guests be informed
that I am not at home.
The vicar was quite specific
about seeing Her Grace.
When I presented the duchess
with Mr. Pointer's card.
I thought she'd actually
run down the stairs.
she was so pleased
to have callers.
How long have the
Pointers been here?
Only a few
minutes. Your Grace.
Well. a few minutes
is more than most get.
Thank you.
Of course.
Would you like a
cup of tea. Adam?
No.
It is a pleasure to see
you again. Your Grace.
I doubt that.
What. precisely. is the
reason for your visit here?
Social call. of course.
Of course?
When. in the 15 years that
you've served as vicar.
has Falstone Castle
ever received visitors?
Not
once. Your Grace.
Not once.
What has led you to believe
that that has changed?
Wishful thinking?
There will be no callers
at Falstone Castle.
Not today. not in the future.
Falstone Castle is not
receiving. Your Grace?
Or you are not receiving?
It is the same.
Forgive me. it is not.
Thank you for your
hospitality. Your Grace.
Ah.
Do come again.
Thank you for...
I will see you on Sunday.
Do not lose hope.
Happiness can be
found even in dark times.
Persephone doesn't
get to be happy.
That is the ending of the myth.
according to my youngest sister.
Ah. but it is the
ending of the tale
according to you
that matters most.
You might as well stay
and finish your tea.
Cook will be offended if the
tray is sent back untouched.
Do sit. dear. and
do try the lemon cake.
Thank you.
Pardon.
Are you sure you wouldn't
care for some tea?
I didn't know I was
supposed to turn them away.
They might as
well finish their tea.
I thought no one
wanted to meet me.
I doubt anyone
in the neighborhood
even made the attempt.
So I could go
visit the neighbors.
No.
No. they may attempt
to return the favor.
-  But I-
- I will not have
Falstone Castle
overrun with people.
Of course not.
Thank you for allowing
the Pointers to remain.
I have been
enjoying their visit.
You. of course. will
owe Mrs. Pointer a visit.
I understand she
entertains half the county
on a regular basis.
I could meet the
neighbors that way. then?
If you want to.
Who else
was at the vicarage?
Mrs.
Milston and her daughter.
Lady Hettersham.
Miss Greenburrough.
Mm. what did you think
of our resident spinster?
She was very quiet.
so I was not able to form
much of an opinion of her.
Persephone.
It's for me?
You should read it.
"Your Grace. Lord Barham.
First Lord of the Admiralty.
has relayed to me your inquiries
regarding two midshipmen
aboard the HMS Triumphant.
Evander Lancaster. as
you have been informed.
succumbed to injuries
sustained at Trafalgar and.
as with most lost at that time.
has been buried in a
cemetery on Gibraltar
alongside his fallen shipmates."
Go on. Persephone.
It's not bad news.
"Midshipman Linus Lancaster
sustained only minor
wounds in that battle
and remains aboard
the Triumphant.
He will. as requested.
be granted shore leave
when we return to home port."
The other missive
is from Linus.
Linus
has written to me?
Mm-hmm.
I don't know how you
managed this. Adam.
You needed answers.
I simply ensured
you receive them.
This is by far
the kindest thing
any person has ever done for me.
Adam. thank you so. so much.
You do that very well.
I just kissed Persephone.
Mm. I noticed.
And. um.
I think Persephone
noticed as well.
Which is a good thing. really.
If she hadn't even realized
you were kissing her.
one would begin to wonder
about your technique.
Oh. shu-
I know. "Shut up. Harry."
They're
getting louder.
Thank you for my letter. Adam.
Linus sounds happy.
He didn't mention Evander.
which worries me a little.
It was always his way to avoid
topics that were upsetting.
But he did promise
to keep writing.
You don't like it
when I thank you
for the things that you do.
but I really am grateful.
If only you could do
something about the wolves.
Persephone?
Persephone.
W-What happened?
You were thrown
from your horse.
Are you hurt? Can you sit up?
Uh. I don't know.
Let me help you.
Careful.
Does anything hurt?
You asked me that already.
A person can be killed
being thrown from a horse.
Until I'm certain
you are not hurt.
I'm going to keep
asking you questions.
What happened?
I can't explain it. Yer Grace.
It's almost like something
spooked the horse.
We are fortunate she
didn't come to serious harm.
Yes. Yer Grace.
Your abigail can have
a hot bath prepared.
That should help
with any stiffness.
There really is no
need for this much fuss.
When you're too stiff
to come down for dinner.
you'll disagree.
Careful.
There you are.
That is very
kind of you. Adam.
You've been thrown
from a horse. Persephone.
Any decent gentleman
would be concerned.
I can have the
kitchen send up a tray
if you would rather not
come down for dinner.
I really am
feeling fine already.
I think I was more startled
than anything else.
When I'm a little
more sure of myself.
might I come riding
with you and Harry?
Atlas can't keep
pace with Zeus.
Couldn't you
rein Zeus in a little?
Or let me join you at
the end of your ride.
when Zeus has slowed down?
Zeus is impatient.
He might make Atlas nervous.
Couldn't I at least try?
I would rather you
not take that chance.
But you would be there.
Yes. but. but that
is no guarantee that...
I'm sorry.
No.
I. Adam.
Ridiculous!
It is too blasted quiet in here.
What the blazes
is taking so long?
So you are awake.
Adam!
Are you stiff from your fall?
Does it hurt to walk?
They are loud tonight.
How long do you plan
to sit at that window
and worry about wolves?
Until they stop.
You should've come in
when they first started.
Come in?
And curled up on the bed
wrapped up in that blanket.
You knew?
I...
I thought you were asleep.
Asleep?
Oh. I can't sleep.
You've ruined the room for me.
What do you
mean. I've ruined it?
My bedchamber
used to be quiet.
And then you started coming in
and making all those noises
while you're sleeping.
I make noises?
And you move constantly.
Loud noises?
What. no.
No. like a puppy.
Little noises.
And that doesn't bother you?
I've grown used to it.
I don't want to bother you.
You won't.
The wolves don't worry me
as much in your bedchamber.
Are they quieter in here?
No.
The way I've figured it.
if the pack ever actually
makes it into the castle.
they'll eat you first.
Good night. Adam.
Good night. Persephone.
Adam?
Yes?
Why did you
decide to get married?
At the time it
seemed like a good idea.
Does it now?
Mrs. Adcock said you would.
Said I would what?
Regret marrying me.
When I visited the
vicarage several days ago.
Mrs. Adcock said that most
gentlemen who pay for a wife
regret the purchase in the end.
It was blatantly obvious
she was referring to
our marriage settlement.
Mrs. Adcock had mentioned
her sizable dowry at
least a dozen times.
so I happened to
ask Lady Hettersham.
loudly enough for
Mrs. Adcock to hear.
whether or not it seemed odd
that some ladies
found it necessary
to offer money to a
prospective bridegroom
in order to bring
him up to scratch.
No gentleman would accept
a horse so ill-recommended
that he had to be
bribed to accept it.
I thought Mrs. Adcock's tea
would come flying out her ears.
she looked so livid.
Well. you compared
her to a horse?
I doubt even I could produce
such a cutting retort.
Well done. Persephone.
I have not pulled caps
with anyone in years.
I'm not ashamed to
admit that I enjoyed it.
I felt like a regular warrior.
Perhaps before I next
call at the vicarage.
I should try on one of the
suits of armor for size.
I could check the armory
for a jousting lance
and simply unseat my adversary
as she rides up to the vicarage.
I would be the terror
of the neighborhood.
Well. if it comes to
full combat. let me know.
I'm rather handy
with a crossbow.
Maybe Harry could be our page.
and we could go
conquer Adcock Manor.
Oh. Harry would
make an abysmal page.
But he might. he might be
trusted with a battle ax though.
We would make a
wonderfully fearsome team.
You see. Adam. marriage to me
might not be such a terrible
thing for you after all.
Steady.
Are you wishing to
ride today. Yer Grace?
-  Steady.
- Is Alibi still unhappy?
You said he
doesn't like the cold.
Oh. it's not just the cold.
He was treated badly before.
Doesn't trust people.
Figures they treated
him bad before.
they'll treat him bad again.
But no one here
would ever hurt him.
Nah. it doesn't matter.
He'll not give
anyone a chance to.
He'll fight you 'till
holy perdition that one.
It seems like a lost cause.
Why keep trying?
Ah. there's no lost
causes. Yer Grace.
Every creature needs
someone who could save 'im.
if they'd only try.
There's many who're hoping
you're the sort who tries.
This poor creature
seems so angry.
More afraid than furious.
Been afraid for years.
Why? What happened?
Got torn apart
and left behind.
Decided to bite
before anyone bit first.
If nobody gets close.
nobody can hurt him.
Welcome back.
Good morning to
you. Persephone.
Good morning.
Good morning. Adam.
Are you wanting to ride?
I was thinking about it.
If you do. I fear we'll be
forced to postpone our siege.
You two are planning a siege?
Why do I get the feeling
my presence is not particularly
appreciated just now?
I would think. Harry. that
you'd feel that way often.
If you go now. you'll have
plenty of time to pack.
But you'll miss me.
I never miss anyone.
Mm.
"Your name is on the lips
of every member of the ton.
Some are saying that Persephone
has left you already."
Thank you. Mother.
Adam?
May I talk with
you for a moment?
Mrs. Smithson skipped this
room when she gave me my tour.
I haven't ever been in here.
No one ever
comes in this room.
I am overstepping myself?
No. No.
Who is this
you're standing beside. Adam?
My father.
I thought he must be.
You look very much like him.
Do I?
You have the same eyes.
And there is something
similar about your mouth
and the shape of your face.
And. of course. you
both have dark hair.
I suppose there
is a resemblance.
Your nose is your mother's.
I noticed that when I first
saw the two of you together.
Are you like him in other ways?
My father?
Mm.
I hope so.
You wanted to speak to me about
something?
Ah.
The Triumphant will make port
the last week of November.
Linus will be granted
three weeks' shore leave.
Isn't that wonderful?
Yes.
The Triumphant will
be docking at Newcastle.
I could be there and see him
before he departs
for Shropshire.
Be there? In Newcastle?
I wouldn't be gone
more than a day or two.
Of course. I would want
to see him off as well.
which would mean going back
when the Triumphant
sets out again.
You cannot go.
Please. Adam.
It. it would only be a few days.
I. I need to see him for myself.
I need to know that
he is well and whole.
to have even a moment with
the only brother I have left.
This is important to me. Adam.
Things of importance
to me should matter.
What if he came here?
But you don't allow visitors.
It makes more sense
than you journeying
to Newcastle twice.
Linus could come to Falstone
before going to see your family.
Do you mean it?
I don't say
anything I don't mean.
It wouldn't be too
much of an imposition?
No.
I'd very much like to
meet the boy myself.
Really?
Linus might make a great
addition to our siege.
Harry would probably
faint dead away
at the first battle cry.
Thank you. Adam.
Why don't you ever leave?
Good afternoon to you too.
Answer the question.
Is this a pointed
interrogation
or of an intellectual
discussion?
Intellectual discussion.
Why do I never leave?
Because I like Falstone.
- Why?
- Free food.
I'm in earnest. I
need you to be as well.
The food is
nothing to disregard.
Cook is a miracle worker.
Aside from that.
Falstone is familiar.
It's comfortable.
So you feel the same way
about the house in London?
You spend a lot of
time there as well.
And you've come with
me to Kent a few times.
This is a pointed
interrogation. isn't it?
Look. if you were
trying to tell me
to make myself scarce
now that you're married.
I completely understand.
No. it's not that at all.
Then what is it?
I want to know
why you've stayed
around all these years.
We're friends. Adam.
Friends don't just jump ship.
I think your answer about
the food was more honest.
Did it ever occur to you
that I sincerely
consider you a friend?
My
Best friend. in fact.
Because of Harrow?
It may have started that way.
You saved my skin.
so I worshiped you for a while.
like an idol who could ward
off evil spirits. I suppose.
But then .
then you landed me a facer
for something
stupid I did or said.
I remember that fight well
but not what we
were scuffling over.
And we were sent down.
My parents were
away. so we came here.
In those two
weeks of our expulsion.
I met Adam Boyce.
the Duke of Kielder.
Still scared the guts out of me.
But Adam Boyce
was just a boy like me.
Why this sudden interest
in our colorful childhood?
Looks frigid out
there. doesn't it?
It does.
Persephone looks cold. Adam.
You should go and keep her warm.
Keep her-
The fact that my
suggestion confuses you
does not bode well.
my friend.
It didn't...
It didn't confuse me.
She is lonely in
this empty castle.
Just as mother was.
Persephone.
I heard them. Adam!
The wolves. they're
inside Falstone!
They are still
outside the castle walls.
But they're so loud.
They sound so much closer.
They are not inside
the castle walls. Persephone.
Are you certain?
Absolutely.
Have tea sent up
to my book room.
Yes. Your Grace.
I know I shouldn't
be so afraid of them.
but the howling sends
chills through me.
I will have my steward
check on the pack.
so you can breathe more easily.
I had always been told
that there were no
more wolves in England.
Our pack is descended
from the last of the
wolves that roamed the area
and the wild dogs that
called the forest home.
Are they less vicious
than true wolves. then?
They are more wolf
than anything else.
But they always give
the castle a wide berth.
I think.
I think
we should hold a ball.
A ball?
Unless you don't want to.
I assumed you
wouldn't want to.
It would mean a lot of
people in the castle.
Every bride
should have a ball.
We are still in mourning.
I think a wedding ball
would be permissible.
Do you mean...
You don't say things
you don't mean.
No.
No. I don't.
Yes. Adam.
We should host
a ball at Falstone.
Adam suggested it?
Adam?
As in the Adam I know?
I am as surprised as you are.
He's been doing a lot of
uncharacteristic things lately.
Barton says Cook is in tears.
What did you do to her?
I didn't do anything to her.
She's informed about
the upcoming ball.
She's that upset about it?
She's that pleased about it.
She's been reduced to weeping
at the kitchen work table.
How has the rest
of the staff reacted?
Mrs. Smithson is rushing about
as though the
ball is this evening
instead of three weeks from now.
And Barton has
simply begun grinning
when he thinks I'm not looking.
Three weeks from now?
But. Adam. Linus is coming
in three weeks' time.
Please tell me you
haven't changed your mind
about his visit.
Of course not. Persephone.
He can be here for the ball.
Why the sudden
urge to entertain. Adam?
First you invite
Persephone's brother.
And the ball will bring
every family of consequence
in the northern half of England
to Falstone at the same time.
That is precisely
the sort of thing
that makes you miserable.
I don't want you
to be miserable.
I will not be miserable.
You'll simply make the
rest of us miserable.
Perhaps you should put an
end to the entire thing
and save us the suffering.
Shut up. Harry.
Harry is not nearly
persuasive enough
to convince me to
cancel Linus's visit.
There's no need
to worry over that.
But there is.
You tell me to trust you.
but I don't know that I can.
There is so much I don't
know about you. Adam.
So much I don't understand.
And that frightens me.
I frighten you?
That isn't what I said.
It really isn't.
Shut up. Harry!
I am happy to see
I'm a unifying force.
At the moment. Harry Windover.
you are a frustrating force.
Harry. now would be
a perfect opportunity
for a timely exit.
Hint taken.
I have faults. Persephone.
like any other man.
but I am not a liar.
I was raised by a man
who valued honesty and loyalty
and keeping one's word.
Now I've promised you
that your brother
will visit you here
and that Falstone
Castle will host a ball.
and no one. not
Harry. not anyone else.
will browbeat me into going
back on that promise to you.
On any promise to you.
I want to believe that.
And your happiness
does matter.
You should believe that too.
I'm beginning to.
Afternoon.
You look a bit
unwell. poor boy.
I'm fine.
I was just telling Persephone
of all the wonderful balls
we used to have
here at the castle.
Even the London papers
were full of every
detail of the evening;
who attended. the
decorations. the menu.
Falstone balls were
positively legendary.
I am certain our ball
will be far less elaborate.
But that's why I rushed back.
It could be extraordinary.
A few changes to the menu.
perhaps a more dramatic
decorating scheme.
It is enough that there
will be people here.
That should be plenty to
fill the London papers
with pages of
shocked commentary.
The castle's always
been more pleasant
when it's been festive.
Mrs. Smithson and I
have discussed the menu
and the preparations.
I am quite satisfied
with what we've chosen.
Mm. satisfied and pleased
are not the same thing.
You'll be desperate
to leave before long
if something's not done
to liven the place.
We are holding a ball. mother.
That has always been
enough festiveness
for you to return to Falstone.
It sounds to me like it's
hardly a ball.
I.  I
suppose the arrangements
could be made a
little more extensive.
Oh. I sound just like father.
I assure you both.
I am satisfied and pleased
with our current arrangements.
They suit my preferences.
You really must let me help
with future entertainments.
We could hold ever so many.
both here and in London.
You'll have far too
much fun to be unhappy.
Will you please excuse me?
All of the balls
you held for mother
weren't enough to keep her here.
so why the blasted blazes am
I trying the same approach?
Dukes don't need
people. you said.
We're better off without her.
Persephone will leave too
in the end. Everyone does.
You
will hurt your hand
if you keep doing that.
Go eat your
dinner. Persephone.
I intend to.
On the desk will be fine.
I'm not hungry.
Perhaps not. but I am.
Thank you.
Mother-
Is taking her meal with Harry.
I am eating here.
No one eats in this room.
You would rather I starve?
If you are truly on
the verge of expiring.
then by all means.
take some nourishment.
Blast it.
It does smell
good. doesn't it?
What a shame you aren't hungry.
Is that a
hint. Persephone?
A hint?
You are trying to
convince me to join you.
This is for me.
If you want something.
you will have to send to
the kitchen for it yourself.
You plan to eat
an entire chicken?
It is not an entire chicken.
And not such a very
large one. at that.
In fact. it is a very good thing
there is plenty to go with it.
Otherwise I would be in very
real danger of wasting away.
You didn't expect me to eat
an entire chicken. did you?
Thank you for the
dinner. Persephone.
Thank you for
allowing the ball.
For inviting Linus to visit.
It is nice having something
to look forward to.
Would you like having more
balls and entertainments?
I would. now and then.
But I miss my family
more than I miss company.
They are so very far away.
It sometimes feels as though
I'll never see them again.
They may very well go
to London for the Season.
You could see them there.
You could see a
lot of people there.
That should tide
you over for a while.
I will have to get my
fill then. I suppose.